For financial summary, stay here. For
full earnings call recording, skip to
minute two.
ICICG financial results for September
2025 quarter with Y comparison.
Revenue 6,869
cr rupes versus 6,147
cr rupees y with a change of plus
11.75%.
Expenses 5,825
cr rupees versus 5,27
cr rupees y with a change of plus
11.87%.
Other income 33 cr rupees versus 21 cr
rupees y with a change of plus 57.14%.
Profit before tax 1,077 cr rupees versus
919 cr rupes yi with a change of plus
17.19%.
Net profit 820 cr rupees versus 694 cr
rupees yi with a change of plus 18.16%.
EPS 16 rupees and 47 pes versus 14
rupees and 3 pes y with a change of plus
17.39%.
Operating profit,
144 cr rupees versus 940 cr rupees y
with a change of plus 11.06%. 06%
Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to the ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited Q2 and
H1FI 2026 earnings conference call. From
the senior management we have with us
today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and CEO of
the company. Mr. Gopal Balachandran CFO
Mr. Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail and
Government.
Mr. Girish Nayak, Chief Technology and
Health Underwriting and Claims. Mr. Sep
Goradia, chief corporate solutions
international and bank assurance. And
Mr. Goro Vora, chief reinsurance
underwriting and claims for property and
casualty.
Please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involve risks and
uncertaintities which could cause
results to defer materially from the
current views being expressed. As a
reminder, all participant lines will be
in the listenon mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need
assistance during the conference call,
please signal an operator by pressing
star and then zero on your touchstone
phone. Please note that this conference
is being recorded. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjie Mantri, MD
and CEO ICICI Lumbar General Insurance
Limited. Thank you and over to you sir.
>> Thank you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of ICSL Omar for quarter 2 and H1
financial year 2026.
I would like to commence with a brief
overview of the recent economic and
industry trends which have shaped the
operating environment over the past few
months. Following that, our CFO Mr.
Gopal Walachandan will take you through
the company's financial performance for
the first half ended September 30th.
During the quarter ended June 2025, the
Indian economy sustained its robust
growth trajectory, registering a GDP
growth of 7.8% marking a 5-year quarter
high and surpassing expectations despite
global uncertaintities.
The sovereign credit rating upgrade by
S&P Global coming after 18 years
reflects enhanced confidence and India's
economic fundamentals, fiscal prudence
and related policies.
Following on the heels of the 100 basis
repo cuts and targeted income tax
incentives, the government has now
unveiled a landmark over of the GST
framework which is expected to
turbocharge consumer sentiment
by rationalizing waste and simplifying
compliance. The reforms are expected to
make essential goods and services more
accessible and affordable.
This is expected to unlock stronger
broad-based private consumption and
accelerate economic activity.
Collectively, these three policies
actions are projected to inject nearly
2,200 to 3,100 billion into the economy.
More importantly, these pathbreaking
reforms are expected to provide a
significant boost to the non-life
insurance sector.
The exemption of GST from individual
health insurance premium will make
healthcare protection more affordable
for households and is expected to
increase the lives covered.
In addition, the rationalization of GST
rates in the automoil sector has lowered
the overall cost of vehicle ownership.
We truly believe that this will increase
private mobility enabling more Indians
to own vehicles and encouraging upgrades
to premium models.
In line with our customer first
philosophy, we are committed to passing
the complete benefit of lower GST rates
to our policyh holders.
In conjunction with the above reforms, I
would like to update on the quarter to
2026 number and dwell on the trends
observed along with their impact to the
general insurance industry.
The health segment continues to remain
the largest contributor to the industry
and accounts for almost 40% of GDPI mix
in H1 of 2026.
While the market continues to be
moderated due to the 1 byN accounting
norm post September 2025, we have
witnessed a significant uptick in the
retail indenity segment of the business.
We remain confident that more
individuals and families will continue
to enter the health insurance fold and
expand their coverage.
Now coming to the auto sector in quarter
2 2026 this is the data published by FDA
auto industry has grown by 1.3%.
The private car segment grew by 2.9 and
the two-heer segment has seen a modest
growth of.5%.
However, for the month of September
2025, private car sales grew at 5.8%
and two wheelers at 6.5% compared to
September 2024.
Notably and more importantly for the
first nine days of Navatri period the
private car and two wheelers growth
stood at 34.9 and 36% respectively when
compared to the Navarati period for 2025
which is a significantly positive even
after adjusting to pent-up demand. These
trends coupled with our dominant
presence in the OEM space give us
confidence for a positive momentum in
the second half of the year.
While the global economic environment
remains volatile and uncertain, India's
strong macroeconomic fundamentals
supported by pro-conumption policy
stance. We are expected to which are
expected to act as a buffer and continue
to drive domestic economic momentum.
Given the supportive regulatory
environment, we expect general insurance
industry to sustain it growth trajectory
over medium to long term.
Now coming to the industry performance
for the period ended September 30, 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 7.3% for the period
excluding crop and health segment. The
GDPI growth stood at 10.5%.
For the referred period H1 2026.
Speaking of specific segments within the
industry, the commercial segment
reported a growth of 14.2% 2% for the
period ending H1 2026. The growth was
majorly driven by the fire line of
business which witnessed a robust
increase of 20.5%
during the refer period and the same
contributes to more than 50% of the
commercial business. The motor segment
growth for the industry stood at 7.6%
for the period H1 2026.
This segment continues to face
significant pricing pressures as
reflected by higher industry combined
ratio for motor line of business.
However, as also spoken already, the
current with the current momentum, we
expect H2 of 2026 to reflect improved
growth levels with the first half of the
financial year.
The health segment including mass health
grew by 7.8% for the period ending H1
2026. Within this the group plan of
business grew at 8.9% for H1 2026
whereas the retail health growth stood
at 9.3% for H1 2026 impacted by the one
by end accounting norm. Speaking on the
underwriting performance of the industry
overall the combined ratio for the
industry deteriorated from 1 month 3.9%
in quarter 1 financial year 2025 to 115%
in quarter 1 2026.
The overall combined ratio for private
players remained flat at 110.8%
for the period quarter 1 2025 with a
110.7% for quarter 1 2026.
Combined ratio for the motor line of
business continues to remain elevated at
125% for quarter 1 2026.
Our continued emphasis on profitable
growth delivered a lower combined ratio
of 102.9% in quarter 1 2026 over 12
percentage point better than the
industry average. I will now proceed to
present a company's performance across
three business segments for the period
H1 2026.
The company reported a degrowth of.5% in
GDPI compared to the industry growth of
7.3% for the period H1 2026.
However, excluding the crop and mass
health segment, the company recorded a
growth of 3.5%
while the industry grew at 10.5% for the
period H1 2026.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 6.5% for H1 2026 as
compared to the industry growth of 14.2%
for the period H12026.
We continue to drive profitable growth
through prudent underwriting, judicious
risk selection and through our multi-
channelannel distribution. While growth
in the fire segment in quarter 1 2026
stood at 10.3%.
We have been able to steadily increase
growth in quarter 2 2026 to 27.3%.
Specifically in the month of September
2025 we grew at 36.4 in fire segment.
We retained our leadership position in
engineering liability and marine cargo
line of business for the period ended H1
2026.
Furthermore, we continue to play the
role of a risk solution partner to our
corporate customers to pro while
providing them best-in-class value added
services which helps them mitigate risk
with holistic management solutions.
In the motor segment, our growth stood
at 2.2% for H1 2026 as against the
industry growth of 7.6%
for the period H1 2026. While I grow
while our growth in the first 5 months
of the financial year stood at 1.3%.
The month of September 2025 witnessed a
sharp uptick due to the festive demand
and moderation of vehicle price
attributable to the GST rate cut. Taking
a motor influence growth to 6.5%.
In an increasingly competitive market
environment witnessed over the recent
quarters, we expect to maintain the
growth momentum that kicked off in
September while remaining focused on a
journey of profitable growth.
underpinned by continuous distribution
expansion and granular portfolio
segmentation.
Importantly, we continue to maintain our
leadership position in this segment with
a market share of 10.4% in H1 of 2026.
We remain agile and are constantly
taking conscious calls to optimize the
portfolio profitability. And a result of
these efforts a portfolio mix for
private car two-wheer and commercial
vehicles which stood at 52.9%
25.3% and 21.8% respectively for H1 2025
has moved to a mix of 54.3% 25.8% and
19.9% respectively in H1 of 2026.
In health segment we grew by 4.2% for H1
2026 as again the industry growth of
7.8% 8% for the period
on a 1 byN basis. Our retail business
demonstrated strong growth of 25.2%
for H1 2026
significantly outpacing the industry
growth of 9.3% as of H1 2026.
Consequently, our market share is
improved from 3.2% in H1 2025 to 3.7%
as of H1 2025. For the month of
September 2025, company has crossed 4%
market share in retail health and this
has happened for the first time. This
performance has been driven by an
ongoing product innovation and sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
health distribution capabilities.
This segment is expected to see an
upward trajectory due to the GST
reforms.
The growth the group health segment
recorded a degrowth of 6% for H1 2026
over H1 2025 with a market share being
at 8.7% as on H1 2026.
The observed degrowth is attributable to
a decline in business generated from the
health benefit portfolio on account of
muted disbbursements in the unsecured
and micro finance sectors. However, on
the overall group health portfolio, we
continue to maintain a disciplined
approach and in the month of September
in particular, we have grown at 10.5% as
compared to industry degrowth of one of
1.8%.
I would also like to apprise you of
certain strategic initiatives that
continue to drive operational excellence
and customer centricity across the
organization.
Health I have has further strengthened
on ground claim support for our health
customers in H1 of 2026. The initiative
touched over 58,000 customers up from
34,000 in the same period last year. We
received feedback from over 20 22,000
customers in H1 of 2026. 94.4% 4% rated
their experience as exemplary which has
given us 4.5 as a rating over five
highlighting the support during claims
processing and assistance within with
hospital coordination.
This reaffirms our focus on
best-in-class service to our customers
during the moment of truth that is all
that matters. Our retail health claim
settlement ratio within 30 days stood at
99.6% 6% for H1 2026, placing us among
the industry top performers and
underscoring our commitment to prompt
efficient claim servicing.
The company launched differentiated
service debts in June 2025. These debts
provide tailor servicing for two
priority customer segments, senior
citizens and high product density
customers. By identifying these profiles
at the point of contact and routing them
to specialized customer relationship
managers, we ensure conversations are
empathetic, personalized, and
valuedriven. Over 96,000 calls were
handled between June to September under
this initiative, generating there 300
3,000 cross-ell opportunities. Our
belief is that differentiated care
sementally builds loyalty and long-term
value. Our
take care app a one-stop solution for
insurance and wellness need has now
crossed 18.4 million downloads
reflecting growing customer engagements
and digital ad adoption. The gross
return premium earned from the take care
app during the period H1 2026 was 2088.2
million with the premium earning of H1
2025 which stood at 8 million.
We have continuously enhanced our
efficiency levels in motor claims. Our
preferred partner network services
service 75.1%
of our nonOEM claims for quarter 2 2026
up from 72.8% in quarter 2 2025.
Furthermore, in the motor insurance own
damage segment, 96.4% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days for H1
2026.
If we look at the industry numbers for
the period quarter 1 2026, the same
stood at 82.4%.
Clearly highlighting IC Lombard superior
claim settlement practice.
Our unwavering focus on putting the
customer for first continues to reflect
in our net promoter score for quarter 1
2026.
We recorded an NPS of 72 for health
claims and 66 for motor claims.
Demonstrating strong satisfaction level
and reinforcing our position as a
customer centric organization.
We continue to demonstrate strong
resilience in face of rapid evolving
industry dynamics underscoring our
unwavering focus on delivering
sustainable and long-term profitability.
Our strategic direction is firmly rooted
in a onele one team philosophy which
promotes collaboration, operational
excellence and a unified approach across
the organization. In conclusion, GST and
other regulatory reforms being positive
for the general insurance sector, we are
well positioned to ride this momentum,
responsibly scaling our reach,
sharpening our value proposition and
converting a more supportive demand
environment into sustained highquality
performance.
I will request Gopar to pick through the
financial numbers for the recently
concluded quarter and half year. Uh
thanks Sanjie and uh good evening to
each one of you. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year. We have uploaded
the results presentation on our website.
You can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers. Uh with effect
from October 1, 2024, long-term products
are accounted on a 1 byN basis as
mandated by the regulator IIA. Hence, H1
FI 2026 or for the matter of fact even
quarter 2 2026 FI numbers are not
comparable with the prior periods. uh
please refer to our investor
presentation for further details. The
gross return premium of the company was
at rupes 151.11 billion in H1 FI26 as
against rupees 148.79 billion in H1 FI25
a growth of 1.6%.
GDP of the company was at rupes 143.31
billion in H1 FI26 as against rupes
144.09 billion in H1 FI25 a degrowth
of.5%
against the industry growth of 7.3%.
Excluding crop and mass health, GDP
growth of the company was at 3.5% as
against industic growth of 10.5% in H1
FI26.
GDP of the company was at rupees 65.96
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupees
67.21
billion in Q2 FI25 a degrowth of 1.9%
against the industry growth of 5.9% for
the same period excluding crop and mass
health GDP growth of the company was at
3.5%.
As against the industry growth of 9.8%
in quarter 2 FI26, our GDPI during the
quarter was mainly driven by growth in
the preferred lines of business. The
overall GDP of our commercial line
segment grew by 6.1% to rupes 15.84
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupes
14.93 billion in Q2 FI25.
On the retail side of the business, GDP
of the motor segment was at rupes 25.11
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupes
24.82 82 billion in Q2 FI25 registering
a growth of 1.2%. The advanced premium
numbers was rupes 39.13 billion as at
September 30 2025 as against rupes 38.07
billion as at June 30, 2025. GDP of the
health segment was at rupes 16.49
billion in Q2 FI26 as against rupes
15.29 billion in Q2 FI25 registering a
growth of 7.8%. Our agents including the
point of sale distribution count was 1
lakh 47,408
as on September 30, 2025 up from 143 675
as at June 30 2025. During the quarter
the industry witnessed multiple CAT
events mainly floods in various parts of
the country thereby impacting our
combined ratio which was 104% for H1
FI26 as against 103.2% 2% for H1 FI25
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees 73 billion in H1 FI26
and rupees 94 billion in H1 FI25.
The combined ratio was 103.3%
and 102.2% respectively.
combined ratio was 105.1%
in Q2 FI26 as against 104.5% in Q2 FI25
excluding the impact of CAT losses of
rupees 73 billion in Q2 FI26 and 94
billion rupees in Q2 FI25 the combined
ratio was 103.8%
and 102.6% 6% respectively. Our
investment assets during the quarter
rose to rupes 562 billion as at
September 30 to 2025
up from rupes 554.53 billion as at June
30, 2025. Our reinvestment leverage net
of borrowings was 3.57 times as again
September 30 2025 as against 3.74 times
as at June 30, 2025. Investment income
was at rupes 25.38 billion in H1 FI26 as
against rupees 22.52 billion in H1 FI25
on a quarterly basis investment income
was at rupes 12.49 billion in Q2 FI26 as
against rups 11.24 billion in Q2 FI25
capital gain net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 6.16
billion in H1 FI26 as compared to rups
5.21 21 billion in H125s.
Capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 2.36
billion in Q2 FI26 as compared to almost
a similar number of rupees 2.37 billion
in Q2 FI25.
Our profit before tax grew by 22.3% and
stood at rupees 20.71 billion in H1 FI26
as against rupes 16.93 billion in H1
FI25. Whereas profit before tax grew by
17.2% 2% at rupees 10.77 billion in Q2
FI26 as against rupees 9.19 billion in
Q2 FI25. Consequently, profit after tax
grew by 22.9%
and stood at rupees 15.67 billion in H1
FI26 as against rupees 12.74 billion in
H1 FI25. PAT grew by 18.1% at rupes 8.2
2 billion in quarter 2 FI26 up from
rupees 6.94 billion in Q2 FI25.
Return on average equity was 20.8% in H1
FI26 as against 20.3% in H1 FI25. The
return on average equity for the quarter
2 FI26 was 21.4%.
As against 21.8% in Q2 FI25.
Solveny ratio was at 2.73 times as at
September 30 2025 as against 2.7 times
as at June 30, 2025
continues to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.59 1.5
times. Solveny ratio was at 2.69 as at
March 31, 2025. The board of directors
of the company has declared an interim
dividend of rupes 6.5 per share for H1
FI26 as against rupees 5.5 per share for
H1 FI25.
As I conclude, I would like to reaffirm
that we continue to stay focused on
driving profitable growth and
sustainable value creation while
protecting the interest of our
stakeholders and customers at all times.
We'll be happy to take any questions
that you have. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to use handsets while asking a
question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
Our
first question comes from the line of
pre chain from Motila Losal. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi everyone. Congrats on a recent
set good set of numbers. Uh firstly you
know uh just on this GST uh impact right
uh the input tax credit will not be
available for the health insurance
piece. uh and so what was the impact of
that in uh whatever the sales would have
happened in uh 2Q and uh secondly you
know how uh going ahead how are you kind
of uh trying to offset this whether
through commission cards or uh balancing
it uh across the product um product
other products that you have that would
be my first question
>> so uh pre I I think u um u September
it's just about 9 days. So and therefore
to that extent I think is honestly too
premature to kind of call out in terms
of uh what uh has been the impact. I
think the key thing to look out is what
we kind of spelt out as a part of the
opening script. I think what we are
seeing on ground I think the demand
momentum seems to be very very promising
and to that extent is what we have kind
of clearly uh got reflected as a part of
uh clearly increased volume of uh retail
health policies getting sourced. Uh I
think the key to look for is how do we
see let's say things playing out uh over
the next couple of quarters. We are very
very optimistic in terms of how this
particular reforms is likely to kind of
play out and in that context is how we
have kind of looked at even let's say
possibly the uh uh eventual impact of
any input tax credit on uh sourcing. I
think obviously to that extent I think
we have kind of I think which is which
is there I think we have clearly
communicated that uh it will be a part
of the overall distribution cost in
terms of how do we kind of manage the
cost of sourcing. So in that context is
what even any related input trade will
be part and parcel of that. That's the
way how we are looking at it. But more
importantly as I said I think what we
are quite excited and uh and optimistic
is the relative uh scale up that one
expects consequent to this uh reform
that has got announced. Yeah, I
absolutely I think Gopar uh press just
to uh put across uh we've been always
discussing debating in terms of what the
sweet spot can be carried be 12% can be
this eventually this stimulus which has
come has been the biggest marketing in
terms of letting the customers or every
Indian know that how important health
insurance is and this move is very
significant in terms of managing a cost
structure uh something uh which any
which said there was always a need. I
think the industry is working to make it
much more reasonable and it's also a
win-win because the volumes that will
come on account of that will also see
that our partners have enhanced you know
income which will come. So there is a
clear play which is evident and uh for
us as a multi-line company more so uh it
puts us in a very uh comfortable spot uh
because we've got other lines also. This
is one component of the whole thing and
we are seeing tremendous uh tailwinds.
You can see our own growth numbers on
retail generity uh which have been way
ahead of the industry and this further
stimulus that comes in also gives us an
ability to scale at a much faster speed
with a responsible underwriting. So the
guardrail which will continue to guide
us is that we underwite in a responsible
manner and then the rest should uh flow
out and get evened out with the every
with the volumes that will come through
it.
>> Sure. uh but just further on that you
know uh Gopal or any any impact that you
would have seen in due to I understand
it's just for 9 days uh but you know
there would that have elevated the cost
ratios in this quarter u in Tokyo for
the health segment and also uh you know
are you looking to increase the
distributor
uh are you looking to cut the
distributor commissions any
communications or any negotiations that
would have been started on the in that
regard.
So one I think as we keep saying uh uh
pre I think when you look at the
sourcing uh objective particularly in
the context of retail health we have
always kind of looked at in the context
of the combined ratio of the book that
we are kind of wanting to write at and
there I think clearly if you see even uh
uh on the on the loss experiences pretty
much uh even if you look at quarter two
or even for the matter of fact half year
I think the loss experience have pretty
much played out in line with our uh
expectations. So hence to that action I
think the portfolio is kind of doing
well and linked to that is our cost of
sourcing which is obviously a part and
parcel of the overall combined numbers
which is what I called out at this point
of time. The way we are looking at is uh
I think whatever cost that we would
incur as a part of uh of sourcing will
pretty much factor in also the related
possible loss that one is like expected
to see consequent to any loss of input
trade that we will see in the context of
retail health. But having said that, I
think what what is more relevant is what
even Sanji was kind of articulating. I
think we will be kind of pretty much uh
kind of pleased to look at how things
will play out for quarter 3 and this is
something that even the distributors
will start kind of uh seeing the impact
and the benefits. uh the increased
volumes automatically translates into a
better revenue stream for them and
therefore when they look at their
overall u distribution income uh they
would kind of clearly realize that they
are clearly far better off in terms of
where they are and at this point of time
no significant changes to let's say
whatever our overall uh cost of sourcing
has been I think anything that we would
incur as a cost of sourcing would also
include the elements of input tax
dissolvance possibly that we will see on
the retail
Got that. Uh goal. The other question
was if I look at the uh NWP to GWP uh
that ratio is uh uh has inched up uh uh
any change in reinsurance strategy which
has kind of moved that or it's just a
product mix kind of a uh change.
>> You you have the answer P and uh so
therefore to that exchange is what we
keep saying. I think uh our businesses
is obviously kind of cyclical on
different lines of businesses. Uh as you
would have seen uh in quarter 2 last
year, I think we did have a relatively
higher proportion of uh crop mix uh
which obviously has a relatively lower
retention compared to that. If you would
have seen quarter two of this year, I
think our proportion of crop is
definitely much lower and hence to that
extent and therefore to that extent and
and the fact that retail health for us
has kind of done very well. Uh I mean it
was Q2 of last year is when we had kind
of largely launched elevate as a
solution and through the next 12 months
as we speak is where we have been able
to kind of witness an improvement in uh
sourcing and which is what we spoke
about also market share in the month of
September exceeding more than 4%. uh so
given the fact that that has also kind
of done well where predominantly we kind
of end up retaining a large part of the
risk on the net. So hence short answer
no change to the thought process in
terms of uh reinsurance philosophy more
the outcome on the net premium to gross
premium is purely a function of the
change in the business mix that one has
seen between quarters.
>> Perfect. Last question. Uh
>> sorry to interrupt press sir. May we
request you return to the question queue
for follow-up questions.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Uh ladies and gentlemen, in
order to ensure that the management is
able to address questions from all the
participants in the conference, please
limit your questions to only two per
participant. If you have any follow-up
questions, you may rejoin the queue. I
our next question comes from the line of
Madukar Lada from Noama Wealth
Management. Please go ahead.
>> Uh hi. Uh so uh couple of questions from
my side. uh first uh if I look at the
commission ratio that's uh in stock uh
significantly in uh Q2. So uh probably
more uh you know product mix and is it
also because of uh longer term products
that we're writing? Uh is it because of
that? Uh second
uh on motor OD we see an inch up in the
loss ratio
uh and uh you know very high comparative
intensity and we're losing sort of
market share uh also in in that line of
business.
So um with with the GST cut uh what
would you expect from here? Do we should
we expect sort of the comparative
intensity to come down and uh some
market share recovery happening over
there and why are our loss ratios going
up despite we being sort of more
conservative in this line of business?
So Madukar I think on the first part I
think again as we keep saying one is
what you rightly answered and what I
kind of talked about I think there is an
always an element of change in uh change
in the business mix in terms of what you
look at uh in quarter two versus let's
say quarter 1 or even for the matter of
fact when you look at even within a
comparable quarter uh but the larger the
larger way that we have always looked at
is in the context of the overall expense
of management uh which as a company as
we keep saying is something that we are
very very conscious of and even if
whether you look at it for uh on a half
yearly basis I think our uh our expense
of management numbers are well within
the limits of the 30% threshold that uh
one has put out uh so hence in that
context I think we are pretty much on
course in terms of what we want to do
and again at the end of the day
commission ratios again whichever way
you look at it will also be a function
of what mix of business do you end up
doing more in terms of new uh renewal
And in the context of retail health that
we spoke about I think that's kind of
doing well uh in terms of the overall
loss experience a large part of the book
that we have sourced also in comes in
the context of as a a new growth and
that would entail some amount of uh cost
of sourcing. So, so a lot of factors but
if you ask us I think what we are quite
comfortable with is the fact that I
spoke about in the context of making
sure that we stay within the guarded
rail of uh within the 30% limit on
overall existence of management to your
>> impact uh sorry is there any impact of
GST uh ITC
uh
>> which is what I call I think uh at at
least so far as quarter 2 is concerned
which is why I kind of also responded to
pish's question I think uh at this point
of time honestly uh the commission ratio
does not have any factor uh uh any
significant impact at least in so far as
uh the impact of GST is concerned. uh to
the second point on the motor uh own
damage loss ratios. I think this is
something that I keep talking every
quarter um for I think we should keep
looking at one is of course is is
quarter to quarter a right comparison
honestly as we keep saying there are
various factors or nuances that go into
uh the loss ratio numbers and uh
secondly as I as we have always
mentioned in the past I think the better
way to look at is more in terms of motor
as a category and that to more on
ideally on a year-to- date basis and if
you and if you recollect just to refresh
the overall Overall motor loss ratio
range that we have spoken about to the
streets have been in the range of 65 to
67%. And even if you look at the first
half numbers for overall motor I think
the overall loss ratio stands that if I
remember the numbers correctly it's
about 66.6%.
So it's well within that range of 65 to
67% in terms of what we want to operate
and hence but yes between periods there
can always be let's say some bit of uh
volatility to the overall loss numbers
but honestly I think what we are again
comfortable with is within the range
that one is operating at
>> and also Maduka just to add to this for
you and everybody else who are you know
on the call is also the configuration of
business if you see uh relatively if the
new business is on the higher side the
loss ratios do tend to get lower while
the old one o the loss ratios are high
so there's a mix that comes in and uh
you know that the growth if you leave
aside what happened you know prior to
September 22nd uh was very muted so we
were seeing lot more growth coming from
the old waker where loss loss ratio can
be a bit more elevated so there's
element also which gets played out uh uh
we and there is also So quarter two
little bit of CAD part that comes on to
play which makes the loss ratios look
elevated. So there's a combination which
has got us. We don't see any challenge.
We continue to maintain our discipline
and we are excited about the fact that
uh the industry may probably see record
numbers in the coming quarter.
>> Got it.
>> On new. Yeah. Okay.
>> And uh just on the comparative intensity
sorry to interrupt you comment on that
actually. Sorry to interrupt. May we
request to return to the queue for
follow-up questions please as there are
several other participants waiting for
their turn.
Thank you.
Our next question comes from the line of
Sankit Koda from Aendos Park. Please go
ahead.
>> Uh yeah uh thank you for the
opportunity. Uh uh Gopal given given GST
cut IDV will come down. So it is fair to
assume that um your your motor loss
ratios invariably will go up uh because
of the vehicle GST cuts and and do you
think the ROE depletion which could
happen because of the higher loss ratios
in motor OD can it be more than
compensated or at least compensated by
the extra float either in the form of
advanced premium or or the premium
you'll collect because of the new sales
will be good enough to to to to see the
uh positive above on the profitability
and and related to that on on TP side uh
given given uh GST on CV has been
reduced and and uh and and you have
input credit benefit so in indirectly it
is kind of a price hike to you guys so
so just wondering that given we will
never that's such a strong player in CV
segment uh given given we are seeing a
bit of uptick in CV segment in second
quarter compared to 1Q whether whether
you'll change a bit of strategy on CV
going ahead or not so so that's that's
largely the question I have on motorb
Please
>> yeah I think possibly Sankit you have
actually answered what you wanted to
ask. So therefore to that extent I think
pretty much uh pretty much uh pretty
much what you kind of asked. I think uh
one um I think on the motor home own
damage side again let's look at it in
the context of what's happening on
ground. I think there seems to be
clearly a lot of festive cheer that
clearly is an element of pent-up demand
and therefore pretty much similar to
what I spoke in the context of health. I
think what we are again uh then this is
there in terms of the data that was
released by far which is what we kind of
also put out as a part of the opening
transcript. Clearly there seems to be a
renewed momentum on ground in terms of
uh in terms of increased uh volume of
vehicle sales and that's an area from an
ISIS alone standpoint where we clearly
have an edge and that's the reason why
we have specifically also called out to
see say that relative to what one had
experienced in the first five months
when you look at particularly for the
month of September I think we have been
able to kind of get back a lot of our uh
uh lost momentum and hence to that
extent I think we believe we are
positively placed in so far as the
opportunity for the future is concerned
on the impact on uh the possible
deduction. Of course as we have again
articulated as a responsible uh
institution we will obviously make sure
that whatever is required to be passed
on to the consumers in the form of uh
the reforms that has been entailed
pretty much on course to make sure that
all of those things will be completely
passed on and that's what we have done
and uh and of course uh as you rightly
said there are those various factors
depending on what volumes or what type
of vehicles are customers wanting to buy
will be a factor to determine how some
part of the impact will played out. Our
own efficiencies that we can bring about
in the context of the business mix that
we write will also be an element that
will kind of to some extent uh take care
of some of the possible impact that one
would uh see on the book assuming we
don't do uh anything on uh on on the uh
on the uh drop in the value of the
vehicle and three is obviously again a
function of the claim efficiencies. I
think as an organization again we have
been speak time and again spoken about
the various claim intervention
initiatives that we have kind of worked
on all of this as which is why we called
out even at the time when this
announcements were made we had said that
all said and done I think from an ISIS
alarm standpoint I think we should be
able to kind of take some of this
impacts within the overall uh scale of
operations. Uh I think the key thing to
look out for will be how does things
play out over the next couple of
quarters. Uh which is where we are kind
of very very positive and optimistic in
terms of how do we see things playing
out on ground on the impact side. I
think we think this is something that we
should be able to kind of manage within
the overall scale of operations.
>> Got it. Got it. Go and and lastly on
data keeping this range insurance
accepted business 462 crores what we did
in sec current quarter or even a much
bigger number in first half it is
largely related to which line of
business uh and this number will
continue even in second half.
>> So again sanit this question just does
keep coming uh to us uh on different uh
at different time points. I think as
what we have clearly maintained is
pretty much similar to what we have kind
of talked about in the context of uh
crop. I think uh these are opportunistic
uh these are opportunistic uh calls that
we take purely from an underwriting
standpoint. Uh whatever fits within our
underwriting acceptances criteria is
what we end up writing whether it is for
direct or even for the matter of fact as
reinsurancees acceptances. But each of
this even if you look at it on a full
year basis for example last year our
overall proportion of reinsurance
acceptances to the total volume of gross
premiums that we would have underwritten
as a company has been clearly a
single-digit number. uh so when you
start looking at some of these numbers
particularly with a quarter I think
there can always be aberrations when you
look start look at in the context of
percentages but if you ask us from a
thought process or let's say from a
philosophy standpoints purely guided by
the underwriting filters that we kind of
put in terms of risk acceptance and do
we expect each of these to suddenly
become a very large proportion of our
overall gross premium the short answer
is no it'll be well within the defined
uh limits that we have as an institution
>> got thanks thanks for the answers
Thanks.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nidesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
>> Uh thanks for the opportunity. My
question is on retail health insurance.
Uh uh so can you share loss ratios on
the retail health insurance and group
health insurance for the quarter and
second is uh what is the share of agency
and non- agency channel in the retail
health insurance? I'm trying to
understand how how we have been able to
show pretty strong growth in retail
health insurance over last one year.
>> Yeah, I was just waiting for this
question to be asked in the context of
the split between uh loss ratios on uh
retail indemnity and let's say the uh
corporate health. Uh so uh so if you
I'll just first give the numbers for
quarter two last year. Uh and first I
will give the group health or let's say
the employer employee health numbers. uh
Q2 last year uh employer employee or
group health numbers was 98% on the loss
ratio. Uh this number for quarter 2 of
the current year stands at about 93.7%.
Uh and on a half yearly basis again
employer employee loss ratio H1 last
year that number was 98%. This number
for H1 of the current year is at 94.6%.
Uh that's employer employee health on
retail indemnity. Again in the same
order quarter two last year the loss
ratio was 70.3%.
And H1 of last year was 71.4%.
And uh if you look at quarter 2 of the
current year the loss ratio on retail
indemnity stands at 65.4%.
And on a half yearly basis it stands at
about 69.7%.
Now just to kind of again refresh on the
retail indemnity book pretty much
similar to what I spoke about on uh
overall motor where to the streets we
have been generally talking about a loss
ratio range that you are comfortable at
65 to 67%. Even on retail health
indemnity the range that we have been
speaking about is to maintain the loss
ratio in the range of 65 to 70 and if
you see on a half yearly basis on the
retail health indemnity book the loss
ratio is within that range of 65 to 70.
So that's where we are in terms of uh
the split of the loss ratio numbers on
the split of uh the business between uh
agency and other than agency. Generally
the proportion of the book that we do
through agency is about uh 2/3 roughly
and the rest of the book will be the
balance one/3
>> and both channels are growing as a
similar pace or
>> agency has been relatively faster at
this point of time uh but it's uh both
of them are in very high zone because
the overall growth itself of the book is
in the 50s range if you look at NBC So
there's significant traction that we see
and uh we are excited about both the
opportunities whether agency or non-
agency.
>> Sure. Sure. Thank you. Uh that's it from
my side.
>> Thanks Sesh.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh from MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh good evening. Thanks for
the opportunity. Uh two questions. First
uh can you please sort of provide some
color on your market share in motor in
terms of new air and renewal uh I mean
I'm asking because if I understand
correctly I mean your pricing is uh
reasonably higher than aggressive
competitors and you have a kind of a
strong acceptance as uh the the points
uh so in that context I wanted to
understand if that there's a wide
divergence in market share in the new uh
v renewal market in motor that's one
Second uh now uh with this uh GST thing
uh uh in action uh in terms of growth
driver at the industry level what do I
mean do you think industry uh at the
aggregate level going to uh return to a
strong growth phase probably in the next
year or so because uh I mean uh in the
recent year motor vehicle sales have
been one kind of a point uh pinpoint
then you also had some of these schemes
fading out of course does not matter for
you much but like crop insurance and all
that have been seeing a bit of a decline
so at the aggregate level what could be
the in terms of value terms premium
driver for the industry probably in FI27
thanks
so uh ain uh honestly I think what we
can talk about is more at an aggregate
level in terms of motor as a category uh
in terms of market share which is there
if you look at the first half of uh last
year we had a market share of roughly
about 10.9% and if you look At the first
half of the current year we have a
market share of roughly about 10.4%. Uh
this is both half year to half year. Uh
within that I think uh we keep kind of
toggling between new and renewal. So
honestly I think too difficult to kind
of call out specifically what could be
the market share because that could keep
changing depending on what kind of a mix
of the portfolio that one wants to kind
of underwrite. So that's the reason why
we we're not specifically calling out in
terms of what would be a market share
between new and what would be a market
share between the the renewal book. to
your second point on uh do we expect the
demand on ground to sustain even for the
next year. I think honestly we will we
will we will obviously play through the
quarters uh in terms of how how one sees
uh uh demands paying out which is what
we called out even about on the opening
transcript. I think the good part is I
think the the the the the pace of
reforms that has been exhibited across
the various regulatory authorities I
think has clearly set the tone on ground
and that's also kind of reflective in
terms of the outcomes that one has seen
in the initial uh few days of let's say
the quarter ended uh September and the
good news is I think I'm sure all of you
are also equally tracking in terms of
what's happening on ground uh
particularly with respect to the volume
of vehicle sales that's playing out uh
at the initial indications even one was
if one was to see in the months of
October I think the the demand
definitely is kind of uh continuing and
therefore there's a clear expectation
with some of these some of these
actions/reforms that has been exhibited
as I said by the various regulatory
authorities looks to be very very kind
of conducive uh for the momentum to kind
of sustain over the next few quarters
but honestly we will keep coming back to
all of you in terms of what do we see on
ground uh across various quarters but at
least clearly the as what one said uh
the tone that has been set clearly looks
quite promising when you look at the
road ahead
no no absolutely right and you know if
even if you look at in a bit of a you
know you get to the second layer of
number the total incremental accretion
in motor has been around 3,300 cr and
you see the distribution of that pie you
realize that you know one PSU itself has
picked up more than 1,000 crores so it's
been a very skewed one where you know
things have moved in a not in a
distributed manner and whenever
something like this is there we'll have
to be very very picky. We still continue
to be number one player as far as motor
category is concerned. We do acknowledge
the fact that the loss of half a
percent. It's more tactical where we do
believe if it's not making sense, we
will uh we will let it pass. Uh but we
also are aware that no one can keep
doing something like this over sustained
quarters after quarters. So we we need
to be patient. Uh and just to add on to
the fact uh clearly yes uh new is our
strength and we do see tremendous uh
tail tailwind and we spoke about it very
categorically. Will that lead to motor
industry per say showing a better
growth? My the belief and the answer is
clearly we do believe so but it has to
pan out on a more consistent basis. The
only element that we want to exist at
this point of time is there was a
pent-up demand which also was there
because post August 15 there wasn't much
happening in the market. Uh our math
says even adjust to that adjusted to
that the excitement in the market uh is
very high and uh we will stay connected.
I'm sure those numbers are which you are
all you all are very well aware of but
we see a significant opportunity in
quarter three and probably even H2 of
this financial year and this should
occur well for the industry uh even for
uh next financial year if that's what
your question is
>> thank any view on motor TP tariffs
>> uh well your guess will be as good as
ours we keep hearing that something is
on the anvil and the industry's demand
per
on seeing uh some bit of a hike or
adjustment or realignment of motor TP is
there in every single forum and we do
expect and believe that we will hear a
positive news on that sooner than later.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Very clear.
>> Thanks Ain. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
Shya Shivani from Nomura. Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh thank you for the
opportunity. Uh I just have one
question. Uh this is on the commercial
segment. Um I mean there have been many
media articles. Uh whether it be fire,
marine, crop, there is increased uh
competitive uh increased competition in
the segment. Now I understand that you
guys are still growing quite well.
However, if I look at your underwriting
profit in the fire book, 1H over 1H,
it's down. the underwriting profit in
the miscellaneous corporate book. Uh I
mean it's turned uh lossmaking in this
one versus previous one. So uh is it
fair to assess that um uh there has been
some uh impact on our book because of
the competition or the price war that's
going on in the segment in spite of the
growth that we've been delivering. Uh
that's just that's the only question I
have.
So, so Sh I think again um I think
particularly on commercial lines uh the
portfolio inherently is subject to an
element of volatility when you look at
it purely from an absolute underwriting
outcome and the reason why we are one is
saying this is uh I think increasingly
you are getting to experience a lot many
more catastrophic events play out or as
a matter of fact even if you possibly
experience any large risk event then to
that extent you may possibly see the
outcome of the underwriting
uh kind of reflecting an outcome which
for a particular given period could be
adverse compared to any other uh uh
relative reference uh quarters. But
having said that I think from our
standpoint I think which is what we have
been talking through consistently our
approach or thought process to writing
risk has been to kind of keep looking
for prudent/profitable risk selection uh
portfolio uh that's not just across
commissioners even across other lines of
businesses and that's the reason why I
think at an aggregate level in the
initial few months we actually have been
kind of losing again some market uh but
the good news is again things seems to
be kind of looking up quite positively
for us when you see the month of
September and hence to that extent uh we
continue to stay looking for profitable
uh risk selection uh opportunities
outcomes on underwriting whether you
take fire whether you take miscellaneous
corporate or for the matter of fact
anything from an absolute basis will be
purely reflection of some of the loss
events that could have got played out in
that particular quarter the real
reflection is I think as what we keep
saying on the overall commercial lines
book. I think that's a book that has
inherently generated us good uh good
cash flows. Uh it has also enabled us to
kind of generate better roe and overall
the book that we have been writing has
been a decent uh combined ratio outcome.
So that's something from a philosophy
standpoint that we stand committed but
as I said in a given quarter or so from
an absolute outcome will be purely a
function of some of the loss events. So,
so ideally what time period should I
look if I want to understand the fire
performance?
>> Oh, sh time period I think summation of
quarters which is there the past 3 years
or so if you look at where the average
is can give you a very decent indication
in terms of where the loss ratio resides
uh a quartertoarter movement as Gopal
explained can be very you know dangerous
to take a call. Uh the long and short
what we can put across very confidently
is there was a cat event there was one
or two large losses which is kind of
reflected but it can play out uh over
you know a couple of quarters and you
will see a moderation in the loss ratio
overall in time to come but the best way
to look at it is dig in the in the past
and see in summation if you look at last
you know 16 you know 10 quarters 12
quarters how does the loss ratio moves
you will get a very clear indication
that this is what the broadly the range
is uh in our mind uh this is absolutely
nothing in fact I can share with you
that the rate which is there on the risk
basis uh we've realized more than 20%
than what we used to and I would also
put across the fact that this was on a
lower base last uh year if you see the
commentary that we had on fire uh the
industry was not pricing it
appropriately some bit of semblance has
come and that has helped uh uh each of
the industry player including ourselves.
Uh but what we not what we pride is not
on the incremental risk but the
selection of risk that we want to write
and that is what uh can be a big
differentiator over submission of
quarters.
>> Got it. This is very useful. Uh thank
you and all the best.
>> Thanks Sha. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nirjhal from UPS securities.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh hi everyone. So I think uh a
lot of debate has already happened on
this but still uh to get more sense on
uh how should one think about you know
second half in terms of growth and
combine both uh any color will be more
helpful because uh definitely 9 days
have been positive but uh but to get a
sense of you know uh uh because we
obvious
impact which started from last 1st
October uh which will also be a uh you
know positive thing uh to support
growth. How should one think about
growth? And then obviously in terms of
underwriting profits and then overall
profits.
>> Thanks. Thanks Nash. Finally uh
hopefully from next quarter onwards we
don't have to really kind of talk about
this N and one by N. Therefore to that
extent I think all of us uh that will be
one set of numbers that we will kind of
uh start looking at it collectively. uh
but having said that uh I think if you
look at uh the narrative that we have
largely spoken uh nearest to all of you
is that uh I think uh on ground I think
which is what we kind of have been
calling out I think we are very very
excited and pleased with with how some
of the regulatory actions are getting
translated in terms of reforms on ground
and hence to that extent I think from an
ICIS alumbard standpoint I think we're
very very well poised to capitalize this
opportunity of growth across uh streams
of businesses. So hence to that extent I
think uh possibly the extent of uh
market share loss that one had seen
particularly over the last couple of few
quarters I think one definitely expects
that particular trend line to start
getting reversed and hence to that
extent in line with what we have been
saying we should logically start getting
incremental market share with the
industry uh overall growth numbers
that's more from an overall growth
standpoint but when it comes to more
combined ratios/ roas I think both
Sanjie and all of
I think in general I think what we have
been talking about is to try and sustain
that ro in that range of 18 to 20%. And
even if you look at it whether you look
at quarter two or even if look even for
the matter of fact if you look at half
year I think we have largely been able
to kind of stay around the range of 18
to 20% from an RO. uh so and therefore
even as we head into the second half I
think we'll be extremely mindful of
making sure that we able to we are able
to sustain this uh but all of this we
will obviously obvious keep a very very
close watch in terms of how the industry
is also kind of uh declaring their
numbers I think we do understand that
some companies have started declaring
results for quarter two uh so and we
will see the directional trend on uh how
it plays out but from our standpoint I
think that's sji if you want to add No,
no, no. I think we've spoken and this is
uh well spoken. I think nothing more to
add to this
>> but and uh just one bookkeeping what is
what is the yield uh right now and the
duration of the book and the long-term
portfolio I have now versus last year.
>> So the duration of the book is about
4.74 years and the yield on the book uh
YTM is about 7.39%.
And on the long-term portfolio uh if we
have that data handy
>> a long-term portfolio if are you
referring in the context of uh on the
business side?
>> Yes. So
the yield
>> so on N to 1 by I think that's a number
that we have called out separately uh uh
Najj in our investor deck I think if you
look at the total long-term premium that
could have got recognized as premium on
a half yearly basis is roughly about 6.2
billion and for the quarter that number
stands at roughly about 3.6
No. Uh that is helpful. Uh thank you.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you ladies and gentlemen. We will
take this as the last question for
today. I now hand the conference over to
the management uh for closing comments.
No,
>> I think great. I think thank you so much
uh for joining in. Uh we run into uh
festivities uh uh going forward. So we
would wish each one of you and your
family members a great safe happy
Diwali. These are exciting times for us
as an industry.
While there are some questions in terms
of how it will evolve, we truly believe
that uh directionally uh H2 would see
far more tailwinds. So we will stay
connected. We will uh uh we will look we
look forward to meeting with each one of
you uh as and when you are back with
your respective holidays. have a great
time with your families and uh be safe,
be happy. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you
on behalf of ICICI Lumbar General
Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us and you may not
disconnect your lines.